<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Oleson Lab</title>
<link>https://olesonlab.github.io/support_our_research.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://olesonlab.github.io/support_our_research.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Get to know our lab members’ research journeys, discover their inspiring stories, and fuel their work by contributing to their GoFundMe campaigns!</description>
<generator>quarto-1.7.29</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 05:57:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Zoe Sidana Bunnath</title>
  <link>https://olesonlab.github.io/support_pages/zoe_sidana_bunnath/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://olesonlab.github.io/assets/images/2024_zoe_sidana_bunnath_headshot.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" style="width:40.0%"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><strong> Project:</strong> Sustaining Crane Conservation Through Farmer Participation: Insights from Incentive Structures and Willingness-to-Accept in Crane-Friendly Rice Farming <br> <strong> Description:</strong> Biodiversity-friendly farming is essential for sustaining conservation and rural livelihoods in wetland rice systems. In Cambodia, the Crane-Friendly Rice Project applies Payment for Ecosystem Services (PES) to protect Sarus Crane feeding habitats by offering farmers financial incentives, technical support, and market access. As current subsidies are set to expire by 2031, the long-term sustainability of these practices remains uncertain. This study investigates how farmers perceive existing incentives and estimates the minimum compensation required to continue biodiversity-friendly practices post-subsidy. One hundred farmers—equally divided between participants and non-participants—will take part in a Discrete Choice Experiment (DCE), while focus group discussions will explore their motivations and perceived benefits. <br> <strong> Impact:</strong> By integrating quantitative and qualitative data, the study will provide practical recommendations for improving contract design and informing future conservation policy. The findings will help strengthen the long-term viability of biodiversity-friendly rice farming in Cambodia and similar PES-based initiatives elsewhere. <br> <strong> Funding Goal:</strong> $2,000 <br></p>



<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> Back to top</a> ]]></description>
  <category>Environmental Economics</category>
  <category>Sustainable Agriculture</category>
  <category>Biodiversity Conservation</category>
  <guid>https://olesonlab.github.io/support_pages/zoe_sidana_bunnath/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 05:57:48 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://olesonlab.github.io/assets/images/2024_zoe_sidana_bunnath_headshot_original.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
